I have to run! I have to run away!
But where to?
I don't...
have anywhere else to go.
Lize!
You not supposed to run away!
EPISODE 7: THE MAGIC DIARY
Oh.
You must now care diligently
for this fellow,
until he recovers from the injury
he accepted in your place.
I'm sorry. I forgot.
I didn't mean to make you worry.
That will be your first responsibility.
But what do I do?
Why did you run away?
I think you know the reason, Minos.
They said I'm a poisonous monster.
Huh?
I'm going to be killed.
Luna would never do something like that.
Oh, this little guy must have
eaten a poisonous mushroom.
Might be new to the forest.
Lize, don't do that! Claude just
told you not to touch the black fog!
Oh. He looks a little better now.
Phew.
Are you okay, Lize? Doesn't it hurt
when you absorb the black fog?
I guess it makes me feel a little heavy.
But...
if I can handle that, at least
it cleans up the world a little.
That's something I like about you, Lize,
but it also makes me kinda sad.
Just like Luna.
You weren't supposed to hear any of that.
Wait. You didn't...
Hey, Luna. The kid's been
sniffing poison again.
We're going home.
Lize?
I can't move.
Somebody help me!
I've been swallowed up so many times
by that dark sludge in my dreams,
but you came and held on to me.
You saved me. Nobody else even heard
me cry out before, but you did.
You're the only one who noticed.
Even if it's only in dreams,
you were the only one who understood.
Thank you.
In your own clumsy way,
you smiled upon me.
I don't care what you are.
Even if you're a horrifying witch.
Even if you're the person
who will kill me one day.
Every time you use mushrooms to
draw the poison out like that,
you're also sucking out the memories
that those mushrooms fed on, right?
Probably along with any growth.
Are you okay with that?
A sorrow mushroom.
Huh?
A mushroom that grew out of
the sorrow this child carries
from being placed in a situation
where he always has to tiptoe
around others' emotions.
He's a vessel,
burdened to serve as the final
container for other people's poison.
No one else can understand
the darkness he lives in.
That poison, with nowhere else to go,
is what will turn him into
The End of All Things.
I'll start being more
strict with him tomorrow,
to make him a magician strong enough to
overcome the fate of a cursed youngling.
Please don't cry, Miss Witch. When I
wake up, I need to tell you something.
"Master, I realize I am
an unworthy apprentice,
but I humbly ask for your guidance."
What is this? I feel a kind
of heaviness in my chest.
I feel like I endured something really
painful, but I can't remember what.
But I think I remember Miss Witch's
warm hand gently holding my own.
What was that all about, though?
As punishment for trying
to run away yesterday,
you are not allowed to set foot
outside this house for a week.
Huh?
WARM HAND
Did I really try to run away?
Actually, never mind.
I was right.
When your mushroom draws out his poison,
it removes more than just
the cause of the blight.
It also eliminates all
memories associated with it,
probably including any growth
he experienced during that time.
That would be a problem.
Well, there's nothing I can do about it.
But that will have a big effect
on his ability to master magic.
You've gotta do something about that.
If you don't, he's heading straight
for an execution at this rate.
The crow is bullying Miss Witch again.
Why does she put up
with that crow, anyway?
Good question. He's a real annoying crow.
Is he a friend? An annoying neighbor?
Some kind of ugly pet?
I'd better go rescue Luna.
Oh, no. Is he a lover?
And emotionally abusive?
Don't let him get to you.
Cut it out, you dumb crow!
And emotionally abusive?
Hey.
What's up with him now?
Wow, he sure looks gloomy.
Give me a break. He starts pouting
as soon as he gets in trouble?
Is he really that thin-skinned?
He seemed okay a minute ago.
I'll go and ask.
What's a-happen?
If he keeps accumulating more of
that blight without even realizing it,
he'll never be able to hold on
to even a single memory.
First, he needs a way to deal with
the poison he collects on his own.
Otherwise all your magic
training will go to waste.
Miss Witch gave me magical
paper to use as a diary.
Starting today, if anything unpleasant
happens to you, write it down on that.
Miss Witch made this special magical
paper from the mushrooms she grows.
She's mixing something in.
And it's supposed to have
the ability to extract poison.
She's filtering it.
She's drying it.
She's training it.
That must hurt.
Huh?
It's impossible to write anything down
on this paper with charcoal or a pen.
Apparently, you can only write things
down by projecting feelings and memories.
Using magic to draw from feelings and
memories is very difficult, though.
There!
So I have a really hard time recording
only my bad memories on the paper.
The bad memories I write down
on this magic mushroom paper
become mushrooms themselves
and float away.
I learned that these are
called yuck-shrooms.
Once they float high enough,
they flutter and disappear.
My own unpleasant memories completely
disappear along with them.
However, I also think there
is something melancholy
about how beautifully these
yuck-shrooms disappear.
Also, I have a feeling that I still
need those yucky feelings somehow,
so this makes me a little uneasy.
I haven't been able to tell Miss Witch
how I feel about it yet, though.
But why do I have to go through all this?
For some reason, I'm almost
afraid to know the answer.
I haven't been able to ask yet.
This diary is enough to clear away
the faint amounts of blight
that I encounter in my daily life,
but it isn't well-suited
for very complicated feelings,
or deeply traumatic incidents.
There seems to be another
method for dealing with those.
You call this a diary? All you write
about is Luna, the cat, and the sheep.
And a little bit about the bull.
Hey, it's your fault for
leaving it out in the open.
You're supposed to keep it
tucked away in your ear, moron.
The only feelings and memories
that stick in the diary
are the ones with no nastiness,
so it's full of stuff about Miss Witch.
There's almost nothing about the crow,
who starts acting like an annoying pest
if I so much as acknowledge him,
but his existence is insignificant.
What do you think you're looking at? Hey!
Because of that,
You were thinking some
rude crap about me, yeah?
every time I see the crow, it feels
like we're meeting for the first time,
and that's exhausting.
Why is there only a little bit about me?
Huh?
Lize! Get up! It's morning already!
I wanna play, Lize!
Are crows in black because
they always act like jerks,
or do they act like jerks because
they're always in black? Which is it?
You know, I could go for a nice,
blackened steak right about now.
Is it because you hate me?
It has nothing to do with
how I feel about you.
Honest? You know how sensitive I am.
I'm glad that it helps me
forget unpleasant things,
but it can be inconvenient sometimes.
When I asked the crow before
why I had to keep doing this...
I already told ya.
He put his foot down and
just got unreasonably angry.
Maybe I'm starting to become numb
to all of the nastiness from the crow
because sometimes notes about
him don't disappear now.
Has my diary... been tainted?
I'm not quite sure what to think.
Huh?
I guess it started feeling futile, because
one day I honestly forgot to write in it,
but Miss Witch immediately scolded me.
Oh!
Whee!
Yay!
Upsy daisy.
It's all bouncy!
Hey, look at me!
Huh?
Whoa!
Are you okay?
Ugh.
You're so clumsy!
Oh, it's Luna.
Listen, listen! Lize is super clumsy!
Your recreation idea
seems to be paying off,
but I hope you realize this is only
a temporary fix to reduce the murkiness.
Um, Miss Witch, is this mushroom from...
Whoa. Ah!
Lize!
Lize, are you okay?
I-I'm okay.
Man, oh man.
Thank you for the food!
Oh?
Lize, aren't you eating?
I'm gonna eat it all if you don't.
I'm just not very hungry. I'm sorry.
May I go get some fresh air
by the window in that room?
Man...
If I write about today in my diary,
the bad feelings will go away,
but I wonder if all the fun
memories will disappear, too.
What's the matter?
You seem to be upset, my boy.
It's not healthy to keep feelings
bottled up inside, you know.
The mushroom's talking!
I am connected to the lord of
this forest. I am a friend of Luna's.
Lord of the forest?
Nice to meet you, boy. I'd be happy
to listen to you, if you'd like.
You should get everything off your
chest and release all that darkness.
Put your hand on my cap and talk to me.
That should help to ease the tension.
I have trouble understanding Miss Witch.
I thought she was really strict,
but she also seems very kind to me.
But sometimes I still get
the feeling she really hates me.
My feelings and memories
are always so unreliable.
I want to keep a stronger handle on
my emotions, but I don't know how.
I'm so confused.
It feels like the ground under
my feet is about to crumble,
or a big wave will come
along and wash me away.
I need something... I need someone
to make a strong connection with.
Hmm.
Also, I can't really explain it, but
Miss Witch has some pretty weird tastes.
Luna, what's the matter?
And actually, I'm not sure
if I should be saying this,
but I don't like her cooking at all,
and that stresses me out a lot.
Everything looks really tasty, but
I dunno, it all has this bizarre flavor
that doesn't match its appearance at all.
Oh, huh.
I'd cook myself if I knew how, but she
won't let me set foot in the kitchen,
and there's no way I can
tell anyone else about this.
Huh?
Mm-hmm. Don't you know about Luna, my boy?
I suppose not. What would you do if
Luna's body and breath were poisonous...
Huh?
And that if you touched her,
your skin would rot off,
and that if you inhaled her breath,
you would become ill?
What would you do then? What would
you think? Would you be disgusted?
Would you not want to
stay with her anymore?
I think...
Um, when I sleep alone, I'm always
afraid I'll have nightmares.
Are you sure I can't
just sleep here instead?
All right, as long as
you stay away from me.
Miss Witch.
Wh-What is it?
Um, I want you to hold my hand.
I wrapped my hand in the
new sock you gave me.
Is that okay?
I need something... I need someone
to make a strong connection with
because I have no one in this world.
Are you afraid of Luna?
No.
Roses all have thorns, and lilies
of the valley are poisonous,
but I still like roses and lilies.
Um, but the surface isn't
important. What I really want
is to be able to touch somebody's heart.
Do you understand what I mean?
Yes, I understand completely.
That night, I ended up
having a truly wonderful dream.
TRANSLATION: MICHAEL ARNOLD
SUBTITLE TIMING: ANDY ELLIS
EDITING: ELISABETH CRIST
QUALITY CHECK: GABRIELLA ALABANZA
TRANSLATION CHECK: MICHELLE TYMON
NEXT TIME:
THE WHITE WITCH AND THE BLACK WITCH